Academic Departments - Record Group 9 WLU.RG.0009
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
- Journalism Department
  - Journalism Laboratory Press Publications
    - Publications, 1944-1949; 26 Item (Box 2, Folder 9, Box data_value_missing_f564cdfb267f4be77ed40b207765f6d9)
      - Publication Announcement for the Alumni Directory, 1949; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press
      - News Letter. Washington and Lee University Bulletin. Vol.43 No.7, 1944; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Lauck, Charles Harold; Gilliam, Frank Johnson
        This copy of the Washington and Lee University Bulletin includes a list of alumni known to be dead orand missing in action as of October 1944.
      - News Letter. Washington and Lee University Bulletin. Vol.44 No.1, 1945; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Lauck, Charles Harold; Gilliam, Frank Johnson
        This issue of the Washington and Lee University Bulletin includes a list of alumni that were known to be dead, missing, or prisoners of war as of April 1945.
      - Mock Republican National Convention. Order of Business, 1948; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        The official program of the 1948 Mock Convention.
        Political conventions; Political conventions -- U.S. states; Parades
      - Program. 21st Annual Conference on Printing Education, 1946; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Graphic Arts Education Guild; Lauck, Charles Harold
        This is a program whose theme is 'Graphic Arts in the First Year of Peace'.
    - Publications, 1950; 22 Item (Box 2, Folder 10, Box data_value_missing_23d2c09d2dd1317597543d2823c5cb08)
      - Washington and Lee University Baccalaureate Service, 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        The Baccalaureate Service program for June 4, 1950.
      - Third Annual Meeting of the Southern Humanities Conference, 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; University of Virginia; 2 Item
        The program and agenda of the Southern Humanities Conference held at UVAa April 14-15, 1950.
        Humanities
      - Information Concerning the School of Law, 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. School of Law; 2 Item
        This folder provides information for prospective students.
        Law schools; College student orientation
      - There Goes Your Alumni Magazine...UP IN SMOKE..., 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        A single sheet with a photo of a crowd observing the university print shop building on fire and a printed announcement stating that university publications would be delayed.
        Printing
      - Nineteenth Annual Washington and Lee Freshman Camp, 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press
        This folder provides general information for the upcoming freshman camp at Natural Bridge, the first time this annual event was ever held there.
        College Students
      - SIGMA NU, 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        A book edited and published by the Lambda Chapter of Sigma Nu for the benefit of alumni and friends. Describes the members' activities for the year.
      - School of Law Prize Scholarships, 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. School of Law; 2 Item
        A one page sheet detailing the Menkemeller Scholarships and Grants.
        Law schools; Education, Higher -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.
      - Washington and Lee 1950 Football Season, Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Department of Athletics. Football; 2 Item
        This brochure includes ticket information and the schedule for the 1950 football season.
      - Washington and Lee University Football Schedule 1950, Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press
        A single wallet-size card with the 1950 football printed on it.
      - Guide Map of Lexington, Virginia, 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        A map of Lexington. There is one original and a photocopy with a detailed map of the the university and its buildings. Drawn by Henry L. Ravenhorst.
      - Washington and Lee University Generals Fund, 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Department of Athletics; 2 Item
      - Instructions for Long Theme in English I, 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        A description of a course in long theme writing in the W & L English Department.
        Writing; Academic writing
      - Washington and Lee University Announces a Co-operative Program in Engineering..., 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        A folder announcing an addition to the Engineering Department cirriculum for 1950-51.
        Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press
      - Catalogue of the Metropolitan Museum of Art Loan Exhibit, 1950; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        This folder catalogues an art exhibit on loan from the Metropolitan Museum of Art
        Art -- Exhibitions; Art museums
      - Washington and Lee University Handbook of Intramural Athletics, 1949-1950; Washington and Lee University. Department of Athletics; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        This booklet contains information about intramural athletics constitution and by-laws, rules, award recipients from the previous year, and directory information for coaches.
        Intramural sports; Washington and Lee University
    - Publications, 1951-1960; 33 Item (Box 2, Folder 11, Box data_value_missing_c75f53a7e851e733fc0f5122fb3bea10)
      - Washington and Lee University Commencement Exercises, 1951; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        The commencement program for June 8, 1951.
      - Fourth Annual Meeting of the Southern Humanities Conference, 1951; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Cyrus Hall McCormick Library
        The program and agenda of the Southern Humanities Cconference held in McCormick Library April 13-14, 1951.
      - Twenty-First Annual Washington and Lee Freshman Camp, 1952; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press
        This folder provides general information for the upcoming freshman camp at Natural Bridge.
      - Washington and Lee University. Opening of the Session., 1951; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        This folder presents facts and adviceve about the beginning of the 1951-52 school year.
      - Washington and Lee 1951 Annual Fund, Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Alumni Office
        This one page folder seeks contributions from alumni.
      - The Alfred I. DuPont Awards in Radio and Television, 1952; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 3 Item
        This one page announcement details the scholarship awards of the Alfred I.duPont Awards Foundation.
        Journalism, College; Television broadcasting; Radio
      - Washington and Lee 1951 Alumni Fund, Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Alumni Office
        This folder seeks contributions from alumni.
      - Washington and Lee University Bulletin. Vol. 50 No.2, 1951; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        This issue of the University Bulletin contains the agenda of the 22nd annual convention of the Southern Interscholastic Press Association
        Press; College student newspapers and periodicals -- Publishing
      - Here is Your 'Gator Bowl Information, 1951; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Department of Athletics. Football
        This brochure lists information for those attending the bowl game on January 1,1951.
        College athletes; Football
      - Washington and Lee 1952 Football Season, Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Department of Athletics. Football
        This brochure lists ticket information and the schedule for the 1952 season.
        Football
      - Washington and Lee 1951 Football Season., Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Department of Athletics. Football
        This brochure list ticket information and the schedule for the 1951 season.
      - 33rd Annual Conference. The Country Day School Headmasters' Association, 1952; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        A map showing Lexington landmarks to aid attendees at the conference. Drawn by Henry Ravenhorst.
        Education, Rural; Virginia -- Lexington
      - Spring Concert, 1952; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Department of Music; 2 Item
        This is the program for a concert by the Washington and Lee R.O.T.C. band.
        Concerts; Bands (Music)
      - The Washington and Lee Concert Guild Presents Irene Beamer, Contralto, 1951; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Department of Music
        This is a program for a vocal performance by contralto Irene Beamer. Professor James G. Leyburn was the accompanist.
        Concerts; Vocal music -- Performance; Concert programs; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press
      - Concert by the Glee Clubs, 1934; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Department of Music; 2 Item
        This is the program for a joint concert by the glee clubs of Sweet Briar College and Washington and Lee University.
        Concerts; Glee clubs; Concert programs; Vocal music -- Performance
      - Banker's Forum, 1952; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Washington and Lee University. Williams School of Commerce, Economics and Politics; 2 Item
        This is the agenda of a banker's forum on current banking problems.
        Banks and banking -- Administration; Banks and banking -- Finance
      - Carmen. Fancy Dress 1951, Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        The Fancy Dress program for 1951, with the opera 'Carmen' as the theme.
      - Alpha Chapter House Kappa Alpha Order, 1952; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; 2 Item
        A folder briefly describing Kappa Alpha's activities for the 1951-52 school year. Cover letter written by Edgar Spencer.
      - Mock Republican National Convention. Order of Business., 1952; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press
        The official program of the Mock Convention for 1952.
        Political conventions; Political conventions -- U.S. states
      - Program of the Southern Interscholastic Press Association., 1960; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press
        This is the program of the 31st Annual convention, which met at W & L.
        University presses
      - The John Randolph Tucker Lectures, 1951; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press; Parker, John; Washington and Lee University. Trustees; 2 Item
        This folder is the program for the John Randolph Tucker Lecture for 1951 by the Honorable John J. Parker:. 'The Significance of the Nurnberg Trials in Establishing a World Order Based on Law.'
        War crimes; War crimes -- Law and legislation
    - Publications, 1979
      - Handbook of the University library, 1979; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press
        Libraries; Academic libraries; Academic librarians; Academic libraries -- Departmental libraries; Undergraduate libraries
    - The Lexington Chronicle, 03-01-1975; Washington and Lee University. Journalism Laboratory Press (Box 3, Folder 1)
      An eight page newspaper printed as a ' Journalism Laboratory exercise by students of Journalism 202 at Washington and Lee University.' 38 x 59cm.
      Newspaper publishing
  - Ethics in Journalism, 1998-2003
    Annual publication of the Journalism Department.
  - Lee Memorial Journalism Foundation
    - Editorial Writers Seminar programs, 1951-1955; Virginia Press Association
      The annual Editorial Writers Seminar was sponsored by the Virginia Press Association. Programs include the schedule of meeting events and
    - Southern Interscholastic Press Association Distinguished Service Awards, 1954-05-01
    - Lee Editorial Award, 1939-1940; 3 Item
      This file contains two announcements about the 1940 Lee Editorial Award Ceremony and one about the 1939 ceremony.
    - Newspaper Management Seminar program, 1952; 1 Item
      Program from the Newspaper Management Seminar held on November 24 and 25, 1952.
    - Journalism and Communications brochure, 1977; 2 Item
    - Report of the Journalism Curriculum at Washington and Lee, circa 1931
      This file contains a draft of a report to be presented to the President of Washington and Lee.
    - Annual Report of the Lee School of Journalism to the Southern Newspaper Publishers' Association, 1931-05; 1 Item
      Southern Newspaper Publishers' Association
    - Announcement regarding installation of united press radio news wire, Undated; 2 Item
    - Washington and Lee Men in Journalism Directory, 1935-1942; 3 Item
  - WLUR documents, 1966-1972; 5 Item
- Law Department
  - School of Law Commencement Exercises, 2018-2022-05-13; 4 Item
    General
    Does not include 2020 because of the COVID pandemic.
    Washington and Lee University School of Law
- Music Department
  Washington and Lee University. Department of Music
  - Band Extra newspaper, 1955-05-03; 1 Item
    Washington and Lee University. Glee Club
  - ROTC Band of Washington and Lee University Christmas concert program, 1953-12-16; 2 Item
  - Programs, 2014-09-27-2014-11-18
    Arrangement
    These are arranged in chronological order.
    - Dr. Grace Bauson, 2014-09-25
      Bauson, Grace, Dr.
      - Sonoklect, Alan Harrell and Brad Blackham., 2014-09-27; Harrell, Alan; 1 Item
        Harrell on cello and Blackham on piano. Held in Wilson Hall.
        Blackham, Brad; Vosbein, Terry; SONOKLECT
      - Jonathan Chapman Cook, 2014-10-04; 1 Item
        Cook, Jonathan Chapman
      - Parents and Family Weekend Applied Student Recital, 2014-10-11; 1 Item
        Hardy, Emily; Powell, Elizabeth; Gabrielson, Tyler; Lee, Stellings; Sullivan, Madeleine; Shaves, Olivia; Schmitz, Elizabeth; Hardin, Caroline; Hurst, Conley; Cook, Jonathan Chapman; Sullivan, Brogan; Harvey, Joshua
      - Adventures In Sound, University Jazz Ensemble, 2014-12-04; 1 Item
        Held in the Wilson Concert Hall. Student ensemble with director, Terry Vosbein.
        University. Jazz Ensemble; Vosbein, Terry
      - 2014 Holiday Pops Concert, 2014-12-08-2014-12-09; 1 Item
        Held in Wislon Concert Hall. Student groups. Shane Lynch, conductor of Men's Glee Club. Terry Vosbein, conductor of University Jazz Ensemble. Mark Taylor, conductor of University String Ensemble. Chad Reep, conductor of University Wind Ensemble.
        University. Jazz Ensemble; University. String Ensemble; University. Wind Ensemble; Washington and Lee University. Glee Club; Lynch, Shane; Taylor, Mark; Reep, Chad; Vosbein, Terry
      - Kaitlyn Farley '15, Senior Voice Recital, 2014-12-07; 1 Item
        Held in Wilson Concert Hall.
        Farley, Kaitlyn
      - Candlelight Service, A Festival of Nine Lessons and Carols, 2013-12-5-2014-12-11; 1 Item
        Gaylard, Timothy; Lynch, Shane; University. University Singers
      - Faculty Voice Recital, 21015-01-18; 1 Item
        Held in Wilson Concert Hall. Widney on baritone, Gaylard on piano, Goudimova on cell, and Jiang on flute.
        Gaylard, Timothy; Widney, Jason; Jiang, Shan
      - Concert Guild, Marinus Ensemble, 2015-01-31; 1 Item
        Held in Wilson Concert Hall. Shafer, sporano; Yonan, viola; Kuipers, cello; McDonald, piano.
        Shafer, Sarah; Yonan, Rachel Kuipers; Kuipers, Joseph; McDonald, Alexander; Concert Guild
      - Concert Guild, The King's Singers, 2015-02-13; 1 Item
        Held in Concert Hall. Hurley and Wayne-Wright, countertenors; Gregory, tenor; Bruerton and Gabbitas, baritones; Howard, bass.
        Hurley, David; Wain-Wright, Timothy; Bruerton, Christopher; Gabbitas, Christopher; Howard, Jonathan; Concert Guild
      - Senior Composition Recital, Thomas Day '15, 2015-03-15; 1 Item
        Day, Roger T. (Thomas), Jr.; Vosbein, Terry
      - 2014 Parents and Family Weekend Choral Concert, Shane M. Lynch, conductor, Joshua T. Harvey, accompanist. Featuring the University Singers, Men's Glee Club and Cantatrici., 2014-10-10; 1 Item
        Lynch, Shane; Harvey, Joshua; University. University Singers; Washington and Lee University. Glee Club
      - Faculty Guitar Recital Loren Pomeroy: The Compositions and Transcriptions of Francisco Tarrega., 2014-10-14; 1 Item
        Pomeroy, Loren; Tarrega, Francisco
      - An Afternoon of Antonin Dvorak (1841-1904), Faculty Recital Marlbrook Chamber Players, 2014-10-26; 1 Item
        Dvorak, Antonin; Marlbrook, Chamber Players
      - 2014 Fall Choral Concert, Shane M. Lynch, conductor, Joshua T. Harvey, accompanist, Johnathan Chapman Cook, guest accompanist. Featuring the University Singers, Men's Glee Club and Cantatrici., 2014-10-28; 1 Item
        Held in Wilson Concert Hall
        Lynch, Shane; Harvey, Joshua; Cook, Jonathan Chapman; University. University Singers; Washington and Lee University. Glee Club
      - Music by the Sons of Johann Sebastian Bach, Faculty Recital Skuko Watanabe and Byron W. Petty., 2014-11-02; 1 Item
        Bach, Johann Sebastian; Watanabe, Shuko; Petty, Byron
      - University Wind Ensemble, Chad R. Reep, conductor., 2014-11-04; 1 Item
        Held in Wlson Concert Hall.
        University. Wind Ensemble; Reep, Chad
      - International Kaleidoscope, Mark Taylor, conductor, The University-Shenandoah Symphony Orchestra., 2014-11-08; 1 Item
        Taylor, Mark; University-Shenandoah. Symphony Orchestra
      - Concert Guild, Elizabeth Futral in Concert., 2014-11-14; 1 Item
        Futral, Elizabeth; Concert Guild
      - Bluegrass Music Ensemble, lead by Nate Leath., 2014-11-15; 1 Item
        Leath, Nate; Bluegrass Music Ensemble
    - East Meets West...In Paris, Mark Taylor, conductor., 2015-03-21; 1 Item
    - Senior Composition Recital Jack Powers '15, from the studio of Terry Vosbein., 2015-03-22; 1 Item
      Powers, Jack
    - Senior Piano Recital, Sarah Min '15, from the studio of Shuko Watanabe Petty., 2015-03-29; 1 Item
      Min, Sarah
    - "The Easter Symphony," University Wind Ensemble, Chad Reep, conductor; Cantatrici, Men's Glee Club, The University Singers, Shane M. Lynch, conductor: Gregory Parker, baritone., 2015-03-31; 1 Item
      Parker, Gregory; Reep, Chad; Lynch, Shane; University. Wind Ensemble; Washington and Lee University. Glee Club; University. University Singers
    - The Martin Luther King Jr. "I Have a Dream" Remberance Concert., 2015-01-17; 1 Item
      Held at First Baptist Church, Lexington, VA.
      Washington and Lee University. Glee Club; University. University Singers; Lynch, Shane; Harvey, Joshua
    - University Jazz Ensemble, Terry Vosbein, director., 2015-04-09; 1 Item
      Vosbein, Terry; University. Jazz Ensemble
    - Ardo Consort: Developing Styles, Compositions by Byron W. Petty., 2015-05-03; 1 Item
      Held in Wilson Concert Hall. Petty on flute and piano, Parrish on oboe, Kevin Matheson on violin, Bryan Matheson on viola, Goudimova on cello, Easter II and III on French horn, Watanabe and Cook on piano.
      Petty, Byron; Parrish, Bill; Matheson, Kevin; Matheson, Bryan; Easter III, Wallace; Watanabe, Shuko; Cook, Jonathan Chapman
    - Junior Voice Recital from the studio of Jason Widney. Emily Streeper, soprano, Madeleine Sullivan, mezzo soprano., 2015-05-12; 1 Item
      Held in Wilson Concert Hall. Cook and Harvey on piano.
      Streeper, Emily; Sullivan, Madeleine; Cook, Jonathan Chapman; Harvey, Joshua
    - Senior Piano Recital from the studio of Shuko Watanabe Petty., 2015-05-26; 1 Item
      Held in Wilson Hall Concert.
      Hardy, Emily; Gabrielson, Tyler
    - The Washington and Lee University Singers. Shane M. Lynch, Conductor. 2015 Tour Program., 1 Item
      Tour Program.
      Lynch, Shane; University. University Singers
    - Lenfest Center for the Arts, Celebrate the Arts! 25th Annivesary, 2015-2016., 1 Item
      Washington and Lee University. Lenfest Center for the Arts
  - Programs, 2016-09-18-2017-05-23; 30 Item
    - Shakespeare in Song, A Faculty Voice Recital, 2016-09-18; 1 Item
      Parker, Gregory; Gaylard, Timothy
    - Concert Guild presents The Cardinal Ensemble, 2016-09-22; 1 Item
      Parrish, William; Overfield-Zook, Kathleen; Cowden, Tracy; Concert Guild
    - 2016 Parents and Family Weekend Choral Concert featuring the University Singers, Men's Glee Club and Cantatrici, 2016-09-30; 1 Item
      Lynch, Shane; Yen, Ting-Ting; Washington and Lee University. University Singers; Washington and Lee University. Men's Glee Club; Washington and Lee University. Cantatrici
    - Marlbrook Chamber Players, 2016-10-09; 1 Item
      McArdle, Jaime; Gaylard, Timothy
    - Concert Guild presents the Escher Quartet with guest artist Jason Vieaux, guitar, 2016-10-21; 1 Item
      Escher Quartet; Vieaux, Jason; Barnett-Hart, Adam; Boyd, Aaron; Lapointe, Pierre; Speltz, Brook
    - Faculty Piano Recital, Two Pianos Go Russian, 2016-10-30; 1 Item
      Gaylard, Timothy; Watanabe, Shuko
    - Fall Choral Concert, Featuring the University Singers, Men's Glee Club and Cantatrici, 2016-10-25; 1 Item
    - University Orchestra Concert, Symphonic Development: Sonata to Symphony, 1 Item
      Dobbins, Christopher
    - Bluegrass Music Ensemble, 2016-11-12; 1 Item
      Leath, Nate
    - Concert Guild, 2016-11-13; 1 Linear Feet
      Jones, Martin; Concert Guild
    - University Jazz Ensemble, 2016-11-17; 1 Item
      Vosbein Magee Big Band
    - 2016 Holiday Pops Concert, 2016-12-05-2016-12-06; 1 Item
      Lynch, Shane; Vosbein, Terry; Leath, Nate; Dobbins, Christopher; Washington and Lee University. Cantatrici; Washington and Lee University. Men's Glee Club; Washington and Lee University. University Jazz Ensemble; Washington and Lee University. Bluegrass Ensemble; Washington and Lee University. University Orchestra; Washington and Lee University. University Wind Ensemble
    - Senior Voice Recital, Olivia Shaves, 2017-01-12; 1 Item
      Shaves, Olivia; Billias, Anna
    - Faculty Collaborative Piano Recital, 2017-01-20; 1 Item
      Yen, Ting-Ting; Melamed, Issac
    - Concert Guild presents Antioch Chamber Ensemble, 2017-02-11; 1 Item
      Concert Guild
    - The University Singers, 2017-02-19-2017-02-28; 1 Item
      Lynch, Shane; Washington and Lee University. University Singers
    - Ardo Duo, 2017-03-05; 1 Item
      Watanabe, Shuko; Petty, Byron
    - Music Convocation Recital, 2017-03-10; 1 Item
      Whedon, Ben; Burnett, Jake; Huntley, Kathryn; Jue, Allison; Roth, Lisa; Yin, Xiaoxia; Gorman, Eliie; Schmitz, Elizabeth; McDonnell, Ryan; Chu, Coralie; Tangri, Mohini; Billias, Anna; Yen, Ting-Ting
    - Voice Recital: French Songs, 2017-03-14; 1 Item
      Huntley, Kathryn; Yin, Xiaoxia; Schmitz, Elizabeth; Fykes, Erin; Thompson, Elizabeth; Wells, Caleigh; Higgins, Camilla; Billias, Anna; Yen, Ting-Ting